<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Contre</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Contre</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:18:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Schwarzwald</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/germany_trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/germany_trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/posts/fungi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fungi&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What initially were supposed to be 370 km on the bike ended up being less than half. However, it wasn’t easy and was even somewhat dangerous. We were accompanied by two sturdy bikes, a Giant and a Trek, both loaded on either side with clothes, food, and a tent, and they managed to handle dirt, mountains, and roads. The trains in Germany were a great help, both to avoid descents rated as &amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo; on Komoot and to dodge 12 mm of rain one night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac setup (Part 0)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/mac_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 20:25:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/mac_setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/posts/mac_setup_intro.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Intro&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VPNs, SSH reverse tunnels, &lt;del&gt;Syngergy&lt;/del&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;del&gt;Barrier&lt;/del&gt; -&amp;gt; Input Leap, KVMs. I&amp;rsquo;ve dodged using the Mac for nearly eight years, but now I have to give in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;WARNING&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;This post might seem obvious to many macOS users.&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Coming from the Linux world of personal computers and having used &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tiling_window_manager&#34;&gt;tiling windows managers&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, I always struggle with using Mac OS at work. I don&amp;rsquo;t like it a single bit. I hate inability of solving problems, the lack of customization and control you have over the OS. But if there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that I hate the most is the fact that, as an user, one must forfeit to Apple&amp;rsquo;s concept of what a good UX is and not the other way around. Having the chance to bring the UX closer to the individual, while maintaining a usable software for the herd, is something they just don&amp;rsquo;t care and I don&amp;rsquo;t blame them. Nevertheless, there are some things I have done to try to make my experience better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GPG &#43; SSH ?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/gpg_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/gpg_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/posts/gpg_1_banner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Intro&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will be a small walk through on how to generate an authentication subkey on GPG and integrated with ssh. First of all bare in mind that will need a GPG key first in order to generate this subkey, if have not generated on yet refer to part 0 of these series.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;authentication-key&#34;&gt;Authentication Key&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to generate an authentication key, as I mentioned before, you will need to have a key generated. Let&amp;rsquo;s check that with&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with your private key</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/gpg_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/gpg_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/posts/gpg_2_banner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Intro&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve managed to create your own GPG key it&amp;rsquo;s time to understand a bit more about how GnuPG works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first question we need to ask is where are our keys stored. The answer depends on which version of GnuPG you are running. From version 2.1 onwards the method of storing your keys &lt;a href=&#34;https://gnupg.org/faq/whats-new-in-2.1.html&#34;&gt;has change&lt;/a&gt;. On previous versions our keys were stored in two separate keyring under the &lt;code&gt;~/.gnupg&lt;/code&gt; directory. Prior version to 2.1 used to keep the public key pairs in two files: &lt;code&gt;pubring.gpg&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;secring.gpg&lt;/code&gt;, you can imagine which stores which.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with GnuPG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/gpg_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/gpg_0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/posts/gpg_0_banner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Intro&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GnuPG is a complete and free implementation of the OpenPGP standard and this is just &lt;strong&gt;part 0&lt;/strong&gt; of who knows how many series where I will explain my basic understanding of GPG and how useful is on my daily basis. If you wish to understand more in detail how GPG work please refer to the RFC or &lt;a href=&#34;https://davesteele.github.io/gpg/2014/09/20/anatomy-of-a-gpg-key/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is a great post that captures the essence of it quite deeply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
