<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Contre</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Contre</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:15:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GPG &#43; SSH ?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpg_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpg_1/</guid>
      <description>This will be a small walk through on how to generate an authentication subkey on GPG and integrated with ssh. First of all bare in mind that will need a GPG key first in order to generate this subkey, if have not generated on yet refer to part 0 of these series.&#xA;Authentication Key In order to generate an authentication key, as I mentioned before, you will need to have a key generated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with your private key</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpg_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpg_2/</guid>
      <description>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve managed to create your own GPG key it&amp;rsquo;s time to understand a bit more about how GnuPG works.&#xA;The first question we need to ask is where are our keys stored. The answer depends on which version of GnuPG you are running. From version 2.1 onwards the method of storing your keys has change. On previous versions our keys were stored in two separate keyring under the ~/.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with GnuPG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpg_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpg_0/</guid>
      <description>GnuPG is a complete and free implementation of the OpenPGP standard and this is just part 0 of who knows how many series where I will explain my basic understanding of GPG and how useful is on my daily basis. If you wish to understand more in detail how GPG work please refer to the RFC or here is a great post that captures the essence of it quite deeply.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
